# John Teckemeyer

Full Stack Web Developer

Brentwood, California (510) 673-8723 johnteckemeyer@gmail.com github.com/TheTeck linkedin.com/in/john-teckemeyer

#### **SUMMARY**

I first started programming in high school over twenty years ago. Though my college career took a turn for another passion of mine, music, I have never lost the joy I had for programming. Now I have decided to leave my comfortable job of seventeen years to finally pursue this passion of mine and had recently enrolled and graduated from a boot camp for full stack web development. I am excitedly looking forward to being a part of a team of like-minded people and getting to use my skills to help build amazing technologies.

#### **SKILLS**

<u>Javascript</u>	<u>Pythor</u>	<u>l</u>	<u>ReactJS</u>
React Router	<u>NodeJ</u>	<u>Ex</u>	pressJS
<u>Django</u> <u>nr</u>	om G	<u>iit</u>	<u>Github</u>
HTML CSS	<u>UX De</u>	sign	REST
<u>Materialize</u>	Semantio	:UI <u>M</u>	ongoDB
<u>PostgreSQL</u>	Mongo	oseJS	<u>AWS</u>
<u>PassportJS</u>	<u>OAuth</u>	<u>Atlas</u>	<u>AJAX</u>
JWT Authentic	<u>ation</u>	<u>JSX</u>	<u>EJS</u>

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Sheet Music Maker**

An online sheet music editor with a social networking aspects that allows users to share their work and view other uses' works as well

- Frontend developed using React, Javascript, CSS and Semantic UI
- Backend developed with Node, Express and MongoDB/Mongoose
- Provided user security through JWT authentication
- Created a sheet music editor GUI using only React and CSS

### **Our Alley**

An online networking app that allows users to create playdates for their dogs. Using the Google Maps API, users can locate nearby dogs that are in the database

- Backend developed with Python, Django and a PostgreSQL database
- As scrum master, I defined and organized the particular tasks needed for our team to achieve our goals and effectively distributed duties.
- A major focus of mine in this project was to implement the functionality to geocode locations to locate other users within a certain radius of the current user using Google Maps API.

#### **Bartertown**

An online trading site that lets users propose trades of goods and other users can bid on that proposal with their own goods

- Solo project using EJS, CSS, Materialize, Node, Express and MongoDB
- Implemented a secure and reliable Google OAuth with PassportJS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Teckemeyer Luthiery,** Brentwood, CA – Owner/Luthier

September 2017 - Present

Handcrafted high-quality classical guitars for clients. This being a one man business, I handled every aspect of running a business on top of developing my craft to significantly improve my product on each iteration.

### **Trader Joe's,** Brentwood, CA – Section Leader

April 2004 - January 2021

Managed multiple departments and provided superior customer service.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **General Assembly, Remote** – *Software Engineering*

February 2021 - May 2021

12-week training program, full-time, 500+ hours, project-based program taught by industry leaders.

### **CSU East Bay,** Hayward, CA – *Music Composition*

September 2002 – June 2008

Music theory, orchestration and multiple musical instrument performance taught by world-renowned musicians.